Hi everyone, welcome to Aisle. Today
we are going to study about the
introduction to genetics for A Level
Biology. What is
kinetics? Genetic is the branch of
biology that studies he editing the
passing of traits from one generation to
the next. It explores the mechanism of
inheritance and the variation of traits
in living Organism.
Mendelian Kinetics Gregor Mendel,
the father of modern kinetics, formulate
the law of inheritance based on his
experiment with pea plants. These
laws include the principle of.
Segregation and independent assessment.
Jeans, the unit of heredity, are
segments of DNA that code for
specific traits. The
structure of DNA double Helix was
elucidated by James Watson
and Francis Creek.
Games are organized on chromosomes
tread like structure in the cell nucleus.
The complete set of genetic material in
an Organism is its genome.
Genetic variants arise through processes
such as mutation, recombination and
sexual reproduction. It
contributes to the diversity observed
within species.
Advances in molecular biology and
biotechnology have evolutionary
genetics. Techniques
like DNA sequencing and gene
editing enable precise manipulation of
genes. Genetic
engineering involves modifying an
organism's DNA to achieve desired
threats. Applications including
agriculture, medicine and biotechnology.
Ongoing research in genetics continues to
unravel in complexities of
inheritance, evolution and the
molecular basis of life. The
fatehouse promised for addressing
global challenges in health, agriculture
and conservation. In
this video we have covered the
introduction to genetics, Mendelian
genetics and DNA and genes, and
the introduction to chromosomes and
genomes Genetic.
Variations and the modern kinetics and
genetic engineering and also the future
direction of genetics. I
think you have a clear understanding
about the basic
introduction to genetics. I
hope to see you all next reason Stay
tuned with us. We are from AIS Learning,
empowering your future.